hello everyone this is Joe brewer I just
wanted to give you an update personally
about what happened over the last few
days as I hosted 25 people in my home
for a workshop on how to manage
planetary collapse it was a truly
incredible experience and for those of
you who have been following along or if
you were one of the participants you'll
know that it was a transformative
experience for all of us we were changed
by the process and part of the deep
realignment in the body that we felt was
this shared acceptance that a collapse
process has been happening since well
before we were born and that the loss of
biodiversity the impacts due to climate
change the increasing human population I
mean you're just go on and on looking at
the major planetary scale changes that
are being driven by human activity that
once we accepted how complex that
changes and overwhelming it is and also
that some of it has already happened and
much of what's coming and the next
decade is a kind of inertia that we
can't avoid that things will be lost
that are sacred and we have to accept it
this basic starting point was the
chrysalis of transformation for
realizing how much power we have to
create regeneration and healing of
ecosystems including human communities
as we move forward and that this
collapse process is going to continue to
unfold for decades if not centuries and
that regeneration is the only way to
come out of overshoot and collapse we've
gone too far across planetary boundaries
we are now reaching and passing tipping
points of unacceptable
accelerations
and this is the time for us to boldly
ambitiously learn how to collaborate to
regenerate the world we spent a lot of
time in this workshop talking about
human development and education about
how people's minds and bodies are
affected by stress and anxiety how it
shuts them down through fear and pain to
the ability to be open and trusting and
the ability to sense and discern what's
happening around them and our group
through a process of emergent
collaboration which was the way I
facilitated the event gave us the
ability to experience 25 people being a
collective sense making organism as a
group we weaved creatively for three
days through very different difficult
emotions and grieving and through very
complex intellectual or academic topics
while also holding to a place of
groundedness in our bodies where we
would do improv theatre as an activity
to reconnect us to ourselves and then
continue working as a group having
rituals that were prayers or meditations
for grounding ourselves and the energy
of our bodies or and the changes
happening and the environment here in
Oregon where the meeting happened so all
of this was happening and what I want to
share with you is that I was doing this
workshop to prototype or to experience
experientially design curriculum for
teaching this to people so my intention
is to build a school for applied
cultural evolution partnering with
people in Costa Rica who are also
connected other groups all over the
world where there are collaborations
arising to regenerate ecosystems to grow
the biodiversity of different places and
to create communities built on economic
principles that increase health and
well-being for people all of this is
happening together
and one of my tasks is to help design a
school for applied cultural evolution
and this workshop was the first attempt
to prototype curriculum to design that
education program and the school is
something that is not just graduate
school like masters and PhD level
although we do have plans to create that
it's really learning across the lifetime
from prenatal care and early childhood
development to the way that our children
learn about Ecoliteracy of the places
and the cultural histories of the places
where they live
all the way through to very advanced
research that is applied to social
change efforts so all of this is has
been incubating in my own life and work
for many years but also in the lives of
many others that I will collaborate with
and I just want to share with you that
this workshop is not the only one will -
I'm already planning to organize at
least one more this year and possibly
another one in the spring that would be
in Costa Rica the one later this year
will be here in Oregon again so that
more people can experience this
transformational change and so that we
can figure out how do we teach the
management of complexity in a time of
unprecedented global change so I'm very
excited I'm very sober I'm very solemn
the experience was very grounding and we
dealt with some pain we had one
participant during a particularly
powerful ritual who experienced
vicarious trauma and luckily we had a
therapist who was in the group who was
able to help that person to deal with
the grief that overwhelmed them yeah
this is very very difficult stuff but
this is the work of culture design and
I'm very inspired and hopeful about what
we can do together so I just wanted to
share this with you as a little update
and let you know that we are working
toward bigger things and this is just
one step along the way
if you miss this workshop don't worry
you'll have plenty more opportunities to
come and learn with me to learn with the
other amazing people that I get to work
with some of them all and by two future
workshops to help facilitate and so just
thank you all for supporting me on
patreon I have to say thank you to my
wife Jessica for allowing me to open up
her home to 25 people that came from
around the world to stay with us
sleeping on our couch and air mattresses
on the floor setting up tents in the
backyard the whole works for us to be
able to host something like this and
that we're making progress and I
couldn't do it without you
so I'm onward fellow humans